# Matthew Zuckman

I'm a passionate design leader—transforming patterns, insights, and opportunities into compelling experiences. I shift design cultures and build empowered teams. I develop product and marketing systems that work across platforms, screens, and customers. And I've got the track record to prove it.

#### **Employment History**

# Udemy Director of Design

2014-2016

#### Yahoo

### Design Director, Communications

Mail, Calendar, Groups, Contacts, Notepad 2013-2014

# Yahoo Design Director, Commerce

Autos, Travel, Shopping, Homes, Games 2010-2013

# Publicis Modem VP/Director, User Experience

PayPal, LG, UBS, SunPower Foundation 2008-2010

# Real Branding Director, User Experience

Disney, ABC, ESPN, Anheuser-Busch, Lipton, Red Lobster, USGA 2007-2008

## Established the discipline of design within the company by defining and implementing key principles and practices; evolved as the company grew from 50 employees to over 200.

- Instituted processes for the collaboration, review, and knowledge sharing across multiple organization levels that created an environment for transparency, mentorship, and growth.
- Established the patterns, frameworks, and elements for brand and product, creating guidelines to enable quality production at speed.
- Led the large scale, front-end redesign of Mail and Calendar for an audience of 300 million customers
- Transformed the team's culture, tools, and the working models, increasing performance for the existing team while hiring and expanding the span of control for the group
- Strengthened the cross-discipline team via models that inspired deep thinking, ideation, efficiency, and strategic alignment
- Worked across the Yahoo network to define hiring practices, charters, and review criteria to ensure the quality of design
- Led the development of lead-generation opportunities by focusing on meaningful values, increasing page views and time spent 30-50% across the portfolio
- Built a multi-disciplinary team of eight teammates within four months; expanded portfolio to take on additional business lines
- Drove the re-imagining of commerce portfolio by producing a forward-looking vision that informed the organization's strategy
- Oversaw the re-launches of PayPal's consumer and business sites, bringing double-digit growth in lead generation and adoption
- Supported LG Mobile's digital strategy by delivering rich-presence marketing experiences for all new phone releases
- Recruited and managed team of designers; directed utilization and billable percentages across teams and accounts
- Led the joint SOAPnet/agency team through all phases of large redesign project: developing community, architecture, and content strategies for all screens
- Grew the experience design practice by providing thought leadership, mentoring designers, and pitching new business
- Worked with company leadership to develop processes and deliverables, defining the scoping models for client engagements

#### Earlier positions

#### **AKQA**

Microsoft Xbox, Target, Nike, Autodesk, McDonald's, 2008, 2010

#### Masters Program Study Advisor, Academy of Art University

2008-2010

#### Senior User Experience Designer, McCann Worldgroup

Microsoft, 2007

#### Senior User Experience Designer, Eleven Inc.

The Doctors Company, 2006-2007

#### Senior Information Architect, Tribal DDB

Clorox, Armor All, Hidden Valley, Fresh Step, NBC Universal, 2005-2006

#### Senior User Experience Designer, EVB

AT&T, Wrigley, Adidas, Leapfrog, 2005-2007

#### Lead Interaction Designer, Enterpulse

Albertsons, 2004

# Information Architect, Grey Global Group

Oracle, Wells Fargo, 2003-2004

#### Executive Producer, Epylon Corporation

1999-2001

### Producer, Foote, Cone & Belding

3Com, Sega Dreamcast, 1998 - 1999

#### Producer, Think New Ideas

Silicon Graphics, 1997 - 1998

#### Designer, Printz Electronic Design

Asante, 1995 - 1996

#### Education

## Rhode Island School of Design, Providence, RI

BFA, industrial design, with emphasis on human/machine interface design

### University of Minnesota, Minneapolis, MN

Liberal arts, with emphasis on economic and political sciences